Okay, so the kernel method was interesting,
核方法确实很有趣
but it gets really pretty when we look at it in higher dimensions. Check this out.
但以更高维度来看的话 它会更迷人 让我们来看看吧
Let's say we have these points,
假设我们有这些点
the red and the blue,
红色和蓝色的
and we want to split them.
我们想把它们分开
The coordinates are these for the red points,
这些是红点的坐标
and this for the blue points.
这些是蓝点的坐标
So again, we try to split them with a line,
我们想再次用一条线把它们分开
and quickly realize that there is no line that can separate these points.
但很快意识到 并没有这样一条线能做到
So, we need something a bit more complicated,
所以我们需要一些更复杂的东西
and we'll use the Kernel Trick again.
那么我们再次使用核技巧
I am going to show you two ways to do this.
我将向你们展示两种方法
One, is to use a circular boundary.
第一种 就是使用圆形分界线
So, a circle that separates the blue points from the red points.
也就是说 用一个圆将蓝点和红点区分开来
And the other one, is to think outside the plane.
另一种方法是 脱离这个水平面去思考
So again, to think in higher dimensions.
也就是说 从一个更高的维度去思考
We'll now introduce a third axis, the z axis.
我们现在引进第三轴 z 轴
And now we can think that we're living in a building,
现在我们可以想象我们住在一栋楼里
and we're going to send the blue points to say,
我们将这些蓝点
the second floor of the building,
转移到 2 楼
and the red points to say the 18th floor.
把红点转移到 18 楼
And now, we're going to put a boundary on the tenth floor,
现在 我们以 10 楼为分界线
and that's how we're going to separate the points.
这样我们就可以将这些点分开了
These two and 18 are not arbitrary.
这个 2 和 18 不是任意的
We'll see how they appear later.
我们待会看看他们是如何出现的
So, basically we have two methods.
基本上 我们有两种方法
The circle method which sacrifices the linearity,
一种是圆形方法 牺牲了线性度
and instead of using a linear equation,
不再使用线性方程式
it uses a higher degree polynomial equation.
而是使用高次多项式方程
And the building method which sacrifices the dimensionality of the data,
另一种建楼方法 牺牲了数据的维度
and now you don't have data in two dimensions,
不再是二维层面的数据
instead you have it in three dimensions.
而是在三维空间的
You still have linear boundaries in this method,
在此方法中 仍然可以得到线性分界线
but you have more dimensions.
但维度更多了
So the question is,
那么问题在于
which one do you like more?
你们更喜欢哪个
The circle or the building method?
圆形法还是建楼法
I'll let you think about it.
你们可以好好思考一下
And I'll tell you,
我可以告诉你们
they're actually the same method,
这两种方法事实上是一样的
and this is the kernel method.
这就是核方法
And I'll show you why they are the same.
接下来我来告诉你们为什么
So, let's look at the points again,
好 我们再来看一下这些点
and as we saw no linear function can separate them.
正如我们所见 没有一个线性函数可以分开它们
So, maybe we need a different function to help us separate them. And here's a quiz.
因此 我们可能需要一个不同的函数 这里有一个小测验
It's not a super-easy quiz.
这不是一个非常简单的小测验
So, I'd like you to think about it.
所以你们可以思考一下
Which equation on the variables x and y,
一个点的两个坐标
the two coordinates of the point,
即变量 x 和 y 的哪个方程式
could come to our rescue when it comes to separating the points?
可以帮助我们分开这些点？
The sum of the coordinates x plus y,
是二者之和 x+y
the product of the coordinates x times y,
二者之积 x*y
or the sum of the squares of the coordinates,
还是坐标的平方之和
x squared plus y squared?
即方程 x²+y²
So, think about it. If x and y are the coordinates of the point,
想一下 如果 x 和 y 是点的坐标
which one of these three functions can help us separate the points?
三个方程式中 哪个可以帮我们分开这些点？
Enter your answer below.
请在下方输入你的答案